republicservices.com 2016-04-19

# Privacy Policy | Republic Services

​ 

## 1\. What information does Republic Services collect about you on our Sites?

When you use certain features on our Sites, we may collect information about you from a variety of sources, including when:

  * You provide information to us; and
  * We observe or collect information about you through technology.

​​

 _Information you provide:_

This may include your name, age, address, telephone number, user ID's, passwords, email address, employment history, educational history, billing and payment information, credit/debit card numbers, bank information, and communications records. You can make changes to the information that you provide by following the directions on the Sites. In our online employment application process, we will also make it possible for you to download information that you may maintain on a social media site, such as your profile, and you will be able to upload a resume.

 _Information We Observe or Collect Through Technology:_

**Navigational information – ​** We automatically collect IP addresses and website usage information, such as browser type and version, the service provider used to access our Sites, use of links to arrive at our Sites and web pages viewed on our Sites. If IP addresses or website usage information is ever connected to personal information, our use and disclosure of it will be done in accordance with the "How Does Republic Services Use the Information We Collect About You" section, below.

​ **Cookies and other similar information tracking technologies -** We and our third party service providers use "cookies," which are small pieces of information that are stored by your browser on your computer's hard drive so we can recognize you when you return. Cookies do not contain personal or financial information. We may also use Pixel Tags (also known as Web beacons, Web bugs, and Clear GIFs) on the Sites and in emails. A pixel tag is a nearly invisible pixel-sized graphic image on a web page or in an email message. We and our third party service providers use cookies, pixel tags and similar technologies to collect information about things like: your interaction with our Sites and the time(s) you visit; confirmation when you open our emails, including the time our email is viewed and whether you click on any links in the email; and sites you visit after you visit our Sites (as described more below in “How is technology used to serve our advertisements on other websites and what choices do you have?”) and, on some of our Sites, to keep track of information you place in your shopping cart and what you purchase from your shopping cart. If information collected by cookies or other information tracking technologies is ever connected to your information, our use and disclosure of it will be done in accordance with the "How Does Republic Services Use the Information We Collect About You" section, below.

In our online employment application process, we separately collect aggregate information about the number of users that apply for jobs, jobs viewed and other similar information to assist in improving that process. 

​

​ 

## 2\. How does Republic Services use the information we collect about you?

We use the information we collect on the Sites to deliver products or services that you have ordered, for customer service, to improve the content of our Sites, for market research and surveys, for marketing our goods and services, developing and conducting promotions, for responding to your inquiries, for other internal business purposes, including to verify billing accuracy, to communicate with our customers about service-related issues, for fraud and abuse management, to collect past due bills, and to maintain financial, tax and legal records. The information we learn from you helps us to personalize your experience with us and our communications to you, and helps us continually improve your experience on our Sites.

We use navigational information gathered through technology to help us evaluate how our visitors, applicants and customers use and navigate our Sites, including the number and frequency of visitors to each Web page, difficulties that visitors, customers or applicants may have with our Sites, and the length of their visits. Analysis of this information is used to improve the content of our Sites and for other internal business purposes. We use information collected through cookies and other similar technology for many of these same purposes. In addition, cookies and similar technologies are used for things like: determining return visitors, on some of our Sites keeping track of what is in your shopping cart, and serving tailored ads on other sites, as more fully described below.

Information that is collected in the online employment application process is used to improve that process, to review and assess applications for employment and communicate with applicants. Applicant information may be shared among Republic Services and its affiliates.​

​ 

## 3\. How is technology used to serve our advertisements on other sites and what choices do you have?

We contract with third party advertising companies to tailor online advertising to be directed to you on other websites. These third party advertising companies place, use, or rely on technology, such as cookies and pixel tags, to obtain information about your interactions with our Sites as well as with these other websites. This information helps us select advertising to serve to you and where to serve it based on your experience with us.

For information about opt out programs that these third party advertising companies participate in, and the effect of opting out, click the following: NAI Opt Out ​[click here](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/) and DAA Opt Out [click here](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/). . You will then leave our Sites for other online sites where you may specify your preferences under those programs. You can also click the preference icon that may appear on some of our advertising served through these technologies. You should also note that our systems may not recognize or honor “Do Not Track” headers from some or all browsers.

​ 

## 4\. Does Republic Services share your information with third parties?

Your information is shared among Republic Services and its affiliates who are responsible for providing waste disposal services to you so that they may communicate with you directly regarding your service and related matters. We also may share your information with third party service providers so that they can help us provide services to you, such as monitoring site activity, marketing our goods and services, hosting a Site, processing or servicing the transactions you have authorized (including but not limited to providing such information to credit card or debit card processors, data processors or mailing services), taking surveys, maintaining our customer database, and administering and monitoring e-mails. The online employment application process is hosted by a third party service provider that also maintains the database of applicant information submitted online through that process.

Additionally, your information may be shared with and disclosed to unaffiliated third parties:  
(1) when it is necessary for completing or servicing the transactions you have authorized, including, but not limited to, providing such information to credit card or debit card processors, data processors, or mailing services;  
(2) for those signing up for or receiving services, to verify the existence or condition of your account with a financial institution, credit bureau or other third-party;  
(3) when it is provided to third-parties under a joint marketing agreement as permitted by law;  
(4) to verify an application for employment;  
(5) in the event we sell or transfer all or a portion of our business assets or merge with another company or are involved in a corporate reorganization or other change of control, your personal information may be one of the business assets transferred, shared or sold as part of the transaction; or   
(6) we may disclose your personal information without your consent if we believe, in our sole discretion, it is reasonable to do so to satisfy laws or government regulations, comply with legal process or law enforcement requests, commence legal actions for violation of our Website User Agreement, or to protect rights, safety or property of Republic Services, our users or others. Except as provided above or when necessary to provide your personal information to our service providers to perform services for us or verify an application for employment, Republic Services will not trade, sell, or share your personal information.

​ 

## 5\. What choices do you have over how Republic Services uses your information?

_Email: ​_

You may opt out of our marketing emails by following the instructions listed in the email that you received. Even if you opt out, you may still receive operational emails, such as order/shipping confirmations or customer service communications. 

_Your California privacy rights:_

Pursuant to California law, our California customers may request certain information regarding our disclosure, if any, of the customer's personal information to third parties for the third party’s direct marketing purposes during the preceding calendar year. Such requests should be sent in writing to: Republic Services, Inc., Attn: Privacy Policy, 18500 North Allied Way, Phoenix, AZ 85054.​

​ 

## 6\. Does our Privacy Policy differ for visitors from outside the U.S.? 

The Sites are U.S. Sites. This Privacy Policy governs the information collected at the Sites irrespective of where you are located when you access, browse or interact with the Sites, when you apply for a posted job and when you make payments or purchases through any of the Sites. This means your personal information may be stored outside of the province, state, and/or country in which you reside, and processed by us, an affiliate or a third-party service provider as described in this Privacy Policy. Moreover, governmental bodies that have jurisdiction (e.g., courts and law enforcement agencies) may be entitled to access your personal information.

​ 

## 7\. How does Republic Services secure your information on its Sites?​

We use firewalls and other physical, administrative, and technical controls to secure the information you provide us. While we attempt to ensure the integrity and security of our network and systems, we cannot guarantee that our security measures will prevent third-party "hackers" from illegally obtaining this information. Republic Services is not responsible for any breach of its security or for the actions of any third parties that may obtain any personal information.

​ 

## 8\. How do our Sites interact with third-party Web sites and content?​

We may enable you to navigate to third-party sites through links on our Sites. We do this for your convenience. If it is not one of our Sites, we don't endorse, may not have any affiliation with the third party sites and we do not control and aren't responsible for their web practices. Whether the third-party content appears within our Site environment (like a map frame), or you leave our Site for another website to view it, the terms, conditions, and privacy policies of those other websites govern your online experience. Please view their terms of service and privacy policies if you have any question about their practices.

​ 

## 9\. Will this Privacy Policy change?​

We may change this Privacy Policy from time to time to take into account new or changing circumstances. By visiting or registering to use a Site or submitting an application, you agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy and consent to receive notice of any material changes in this Privacy Policy or material changes in our collection, use or disclosure of your personal information as specified in this Privacy Policy, by postings on the Sites or by email, as determined by Republic Services. We will update the effective date of the Privacy Policy at the time a change is made.

​​​​

​ 

## 10\. How can I contact Republic Services?

To modify your personal information, contact us at [CorporateOffice@RepublicServices.com](mailto:CorporateOffice@RepublicServices.com). We will make every effort to respond to your requests in a timely manner.

There are known methods that spammers can use to hide their identity by using other people's email addresses to send out emails. If you have any question about the genuineness of an email you receive that appears to be from us or the Sites, contact us at [CorporateOffice@RepublicServices.com](mailto:CorporateOffice@RepublicServices.com) and do not furnish personal information in response to the email.

If you believe Republic Services has not adhered to these practices or if you have any concerns related to this Privacy Policy, please notify us by e-mail at [CorporateOffice@RepublicServices.com](mailto:CorporateOffice@RepublicServices.com)​, or write us at: Republic Services, Inc., Attn: Privacy Policy, 18500 North Allied Way, Phoenix, AZ 85054 making sure to include your name and mailing address or telephone number so that we can contact you.
